Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Caricatures and Cartoons 1643, 1756-1943, 1977 PR 10
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Jacksonian Period, 1828-1840
  - "Is Miss Dinah at home?..." [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-1)
    Published by S. Hart, Philadelphia. C. [Clay] fecit.
  - "How you find yourself..." [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-2)
  - "Dat is bery fine, Mr Mortimer..." [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-3)
    Published by S. Hart, Philadelphia, Clay fecit.
  - What you tink of my new poke bonnet Frederick Augustus? [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-4)
    Published by S. hart, Philadelphia, Clay fecit.
  - I'm a 'ministration man !! [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-5)
    Published by S. Hart, Philadelphia, C. [Clay] fecit.
  - How you like de Waltz, Mr. Lorenzo? [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-6)
    Published by S. Hart, Clay, fecit.
  - Have you any flesh coloured silk stockings, young man? [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-7)
    Published by S. Hart, Philadelphia.
  - Behold thou art fair Deborah... [social manners], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-8)
    Published by S. Hart, Philadelphia
  - Good evening Miss, shall I have the pleasure of walking with you? [social manners], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-9)
    Published by S. Hart, Philadelphia. For fecit: Abbreviation for Monsieur followed by a sketch of a key.
  - Life in Washington, The Rencontre [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-10)
    Lithography by Imbert. On front, acquisition(?) date: April 6/99
  - Life in New York. Hab you a few quires of letter paper... [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-11)
    Published by A. Imbert, New York. On back, acquisition(?) date: Nov. 12/03.
  - Life in New York. Black Pink, or Going the Whole Figure. [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-12)
    Published by A. Imbert, New York.
  - The Nation's Bulwark. [Satire on Militia], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-13)
    Published for the Proprietors by R.H. Hobson, Philadelphia. Etching by E.W. Clay. On back, aquisition(?) date: Feb. 25/96.
  - Life in New York. The Inconveniency of Tight-Lacing [Social Satire], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-14)
    Lithography by Imbert.
  - Life in New York. Police Office [Social Life of Emancipated Slaves], 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-15)
    Signed [Dominico] Canova. Lithography attributed to Imbert.
  - The Fashion Behind but Not Behind the Fashion, 1829 (Folder FF-26, Item 1829-16)
    Published by T. McLean.
  - Explosion of the Safety Fund Bubble [Jackson and U.S. Bank], 1830 (Folder FF-27, Item 1830-1)
    At bottom, "From a big picter painted for the Albany Regency by Zek Downing Historical Painter to Uncle Jack and Jineral Jackson." Published by E. Bisbee.
  - The Rats Entering a New House [Jackson], circa 1830 (Folder FF-27, Item 1830-2)
    Pencil note at bottom: "Weitenkampf dates this 1830". Stamped at bottom, "From Judge Mitchells Collection". On back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Tried Friends, Or Candidates for Sing-Sing, circa 1830 (Folder FF-27, Item 1830-4)
    Published by H. Anstice. (penciled note "Hy Anstice at 214 Broadway [1830-1]). Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 20, 1944.
  - A Downright Gabbler, or a Goose that Deserves to be Hissed_ [Fanny Wright], circa 1830 (Folder FF-27, Item 1830-6)
    Published by J. Akin, Philadelphia.
  - The Man Wot Wants Reform, 1830 (Folder FF-27, Item 1830-7)
    Imbert, lith.; published by Hy Anstice. Pencilled note at bottom: "Hy Anstice 214 Broadway, 1830-1"
  - "The Crack'd Joke" and A Late Student, circa 1830 (Folder FF-27, Item 1830-8)
    Faint date on back might be 1956
  - The Rats Leaving a Falling House [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-1)
    One of 2 copies (other 1831-2). At the top on the front side is pasted a note with a printed poem called "Impromptu, on reading Gen. Jackson's letter to Mr. Ingham." Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - The Rats Leaving a Falling House [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-2)
    2nd. Variant. Lithograph: Washington, 1831. Attributed to E.W. Clay by Murrell. Stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" On back stamped, "Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - A Cabinet Maker [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-3)
    2 copies. Attributed to D. Canova. Entered ... by A. Imbert ....1831. Copy 1 on the back has acquisition(?) date of, Nov. 16, 1942. Copy 2 is stamped on front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting."
  - Exhibition of Cabinet Pictures [Pen note:Caricatures ridiculing the breaking up of the first cabinet of Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-4)
    Snooks, del. Attributed to D.C. Johnston by Harvard University Library.
  - The Rats Caught [Jackson/Van Buren], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-5)
    Card catalogue says there are 2 copies but only Copy 1 is in the folder. Published by A. Imbert. Copy 1 on back: acquisition(?) date, Nov. 16, 1942.
  - A Political Game of Brag, Or the Best Hand Out of Four. [Jackson Administration], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-6)
    Lithograph of Pendleton. On front, stamped, "From Judge Mitchells Collection"and on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - .00001 - The Value of a Unit with Four Cyphers Going before It. [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-7)
    [Picture of a Cock] of the walk, fecit. Published by E.W. Clay, Philadelphia. One of three variants. Pencilled notes in the margins of who the caricatures are. Stamped on the front, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - .00001 - The Value of a Unit with Four Cyphers Going before It. [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-8)
    [Picture of Cock] on the Walk, fecit. Published by E.W. Clay, Philadelphia, 2nd. Edition. Acquisition(?) date on front:, date, July 2/03.
  - .00001 - The Value of a Unit with Four Cyphers Going before It. [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-9)
    Third variant with no publisher or engraver given.
  - Tug of the Coalition [Jackson Administration], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-10)
    By D. Canova. Margin notes as to caricatures. Acquisition(?) date on back: On back, dated Nov. 16, 1942.
  - The Man! The Jack Ass. [Jackson], 1831 (Folder FF-27, Item 1831-11)
    Sold by J. Akins, Lithographer, Philadelphia. Stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900."
  - Old NIck in Wall Street, circa 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-1)
    Published by A. Imbert. Weitenkampf dates this. Acquisition(?) date on back: On back, dated Nov. 16, 1942
  - The Rejected Minister [Jackson/Van Buren], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-2)
    One of two variants (see 1832-3). Tinted lithograph. On front, stamped, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - The Rejected Minister [Jackson/Van Buren], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-3)
    Second of two variants. Published by H. Anstice, New York. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - The Trollope Family, from a sketch taken from life, made in Cincinnati in 1829. [Mrs. Trollope], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-4)
    Published by Childs & Inman Lithographers. Acquisition(?) date on front: Dec 2/98.
  - Fixing a Block-Head to the Constitution, Or Putting a Wart on the Nose of Old Ironsides [Jackson], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-5)
    Lithograph by Imbert. Dated by Dr. C.S. Brigham.
  - Nullification, Or, a Peep at South Carolina in 1832-3. (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-6)
    At bottom: "The Union Pie, No. 1. Being the first one, and Introduction to the Collection of Ten Pictures illustrating the rise, progress & issue of the whole subject of Nullification by an artist & politician from South Carolina: price 25 cents each -- New-York". Acquisition(?) date on back: January 20, 1931.
  - King Andrew The First [Jackson], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-7)
    This is a broadside, the top of which carries a lithograph caricature of Andrew Jackson. At bottom of broadside, stamped "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Congressional Elephant, or Last Desperate Pull for Power [Jackson], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-8)
    Weitenkampf dates this. On front, stamped "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and on back "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Colection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - The Albany Regency Dividing the Spoils. [Banks, New York Democratic Party], 1832 (Folder FF-146, Item 1832-9)
    Signed Christopher Sly fecit
  - [No Title: Man drives cart labeled "Courier and Enquirer" and horses named "Biddle" and "Burrows"] [Nicholas Biddle and the U.S. Bank], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-10)
  - "Born to Command" King Andrew The First [Jacksn], 1832 (Folder FF-28, Item 1832-11)
    Variant to 1832-7 but the broadside edition has 20 lines of text below caricature. On front stamped, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Nullification ... Despotism [South Carolina, Calhoun], 1833 (Folder FF-29, Item 1833-1)
    Published by Endicott and Sweett. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - The Downfall of Mother Bank. [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-29, Item 1833-2)
    2 copies. Both copies state, "Draw'd off from Natur by Zek Downing, Neffu to Major Jack Downing." Printed and Published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Copy 1 is colored and dated (acquisition?) on back, 10/6/61. Copy 2 is black & white and stamped on back, "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900" and (acquisition?) dated 27/1/1908.
  - The Downfall of Mother Bank. [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-29, Item 1833-3)
    A variant of 1833-2 - The Jackson figure is on the left. This edition was published by E.W. Clay, New York. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - Cooking Over Done, or View of the Kitchen Cabinet in Distress & Major Downing preparing to read his paper before the Cabinet., 1833 (Folder FF-29, Item 1833-4)
    Below: "From Uncle Ephraim's big picter, draw'd off from Nater by Zek Downing, Historical Painter to Uncle Jack and Jineral Jackson" Published by E. Bisbee at 95 Canal Street, NY. Acquisition(?) date on back: Jan 20, 1931. Card catalogue states that there are 2 copies (one colored), there is only 1 in folder and recorded in binder from 1990s.
  - Major Downing Queling the Riot in the Kitchen Cabinet., 1833 (Folder FF-29, Item 1833-5)
    Published and sold by E. Bisbee, 95 Canal Street, NY. Acquisition(?) date on back: Aug. 15, 1939.
  - Political Firmament [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-29, Item 1833-6)
    Below: "From a big picter painted for the Nation by Zek Downing, Historical Painter to Uncle Jack and Jineral Jackson. ... As seen through Martin van Buren's newly invented Patent Magic High Pressure Cabinet Spectacles." Card Catalogue states that there are 2 copies (one in color) but only Copy 1 is in folder and noted in 1990s binder.
  - The Political Barbecue. Going the Whole Hog. [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-7)
    One of three variants. This edition colored. Below: "From Henry Clay, Esq's big picter; draw'd off from Nater by Zek Downing, Historical Painter to Uncle Jack & Jineral Jackson ... Second Edition" Published by E. Bisbee.
  - The Political Barbecue. Going the Whole Hog. [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-8)
    Second variant. Below: "From Mr. Van Buren's big picter, draw'd off from Nater by Zek Downing, Historical Painter to Uncle Jack and Jineral Jackson" Published by E. Brisbee. Acquisition(?) date on back: Jan. 21, 1931.
  - The Political Barbecue [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-9)
    Below: "From Henry Clay, Esq's big picter; draw'd off from Nater by Zek Downing, Historical Painter to Uncle Jack & Jineral Jackson ... Second Edition" Published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front: May 27/04.
  - The Effects of General Emancipation (Women's Enslavement to Fashion), 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-10)
    Below: "Mrs. Kentelo's New Machine for Winding up the Ladies." Published by A. Imbert. Acquisition(?) date on back: Oct. 15, 1943 Beekman Family Assoc.
  - Immediate Emancipation Illustrated [Slavery], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-11)
    Weitenkampf dates this. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - [Congressional Elephant] or Last Desperate Pull for Power [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-12)
    [Congressional Elephant] cropped off. See 1832-8 for complete version. Weitenkampf dates this. Acquisition(?) date on front: June 3/08.
  - Political Quixotism, Showing the Consequences of Sleeping in Patent Magic Spectacles [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-13)
    2 copies (one colored). Below: "The Diplomatic Hercules, Attacking the Political Hydra,..." Zek Downing, Historical Painter... Published by E. Bisbee. Acquisition(?) date on back of Copy 2:, Aug. 15, 1939.
  - The Doctors Puzzled, Or the Desperate Case of Mother U.S. Bank, 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-14)
    Published and for sale by A. Imbert.
  - The Grand National Caravan Moving East [Jackson's Trip to Boston], 1833 (Folder FF-30, Item 1833-15)
    2 Copies. Drawn by Hassan Straightshanks, under the immediate superintendence of Maj. Jack Downing. Entered ... by E. and S. New York ... 1833. Acquisition(?) date on front of Copy 1: July 31/06. Acquisition(?) date on back of Copy 2: Jan. 20, 1931.
  - The Kitchen Cabinet, or Political Money Changers [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-16)
    Entered ... 1833 by C.H. Evans ...Published 155 Broadway N.Y. Acquisition date on back: Jan. 20, 1931, Wm. L. Brower, Donor.
  - Troubled Treasures [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-17)
    Below: Shewing the beneficial Effects of Clay & Co.'s Highly Approved Congress Water administered to a very old man sick of the Deposite Fever caused by wearing Van Buren's newly invented Patent Magic High Pressure Cabinet Spectacles. Drawn by Zeck Downing. Published by R. Bisbee. Acquisition(?) date on back: Jan. 20, 1931.
  - Troubled Treasures [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-18)
    Hand-colored variant of 1833-17. Second Edition. Published by E. Bisbee. Drawn by Zek Downing. Acquisition(?) date on back: Aug. 15, 1939.
  - The Model of a Republican President [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-19)
    Published by A. Imbert.
  - Trying the Experiment [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-20)
    Drawn by Zek Downing; Published by E. Bisbee. Acquisition(?) date on back: Aug. 15, 1939.
  - "Let Every One Take Care of Himself" [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-21)
    Esop, Jr. fecit. Published and for sale by Imbert.
  - The Skaters [Social/Humane Society], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-22)
    Lith. of D.W. Kellogg & Co., Hartford, Conn. Acquisition(?) date on front: March 7/03
  - See Saw in Danger [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-23)
    Published by A. Imbert. Acquisition(?) date on back, under linen: Jan 20, 1931(?)
  - [No Title] Eight stanzas of verse separated by seven pillars beginning The Kitchen Cabinet ... [Jackson], 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-24)
    No imprint. Acquisition(?) date on back: Aug. 15, 1939.
  - A Confederacy Against the Constitution and the Rights of the People with an Historical View of the Component Parts of this Diabolical Transaction, 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item 1833-25)
    Signed monogram: F [or T] C. Weitenkampf dates this.
  - Emigration--Detailing the Progress and Vicissitudes of an Emigrant, 1833 (Folder FF-31, Item no number)
    A 15-panel narrative by C.J. Grant illustrating the difficulties faced by English emigrants getting to, and after arriving in, North America, including snakes, alligators, disease, cannibals, homesickness, and poverty. The panels are cut from the original broadsheet and attached individually to 8" x 9" backing. An image of the full sheet can be found at https://www.loc.gov/pictures/item/96509506/. These panels were originally incorrectly dated at N-YHS as 1848 and were formerly coded as items 1848-31 through 1848-45.
  - Plain Sewing Done Here, Symptoms of a Locked Jaw [Jackson], c1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-1)
    2 copies. Lithograph by D.C.J. (D.C. Johnston). Acquisition(?) date on front of Copy 1: Apr. 3/05. Stamped on front of Copy 2, "From Judge Mitchells Collection" and on back "The Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900, Collection of United States Naval Prints and Painting"
  - Andrew Resolute Uncle Sam's Faithful Teamster... [Jackson], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-2)
    Wiliams, Del. and Lith. Published and sold by M. Williams, New York. Acquisition(?) date on back: Jan. 20, 1931
  - Not Very Like a Whale but Very Like a Fish, Seventh Ward Promenades [Gulian C. Verplanck], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-3)
    Lithograph signed A. Shad, del. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - Explosion of Biddle & Cos. Congress Water Fount. [Jackson], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-4)
    Drawn by Zek Downing, Neffu to Major Jack Downing. Published by A. Imbert.
  - The People Putting Responsibility to the Test, or The Downfall of the Kitchen Cabinet and Collar Presses [Jackson], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-5)
    Lithograph: T.W. Whitley, alias Sir Joshua invt. Published T.W. Whitley. Donor information obscured under linen, but appears to be Brower.
  - This is the House that Jack Built [Jackson], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-6)
    2 copies. Top: United States Bank; Below: Nine compartments with a drawing in each. Lithograph by E.W. Clay inv. & Fecit. Published by A. Imbert.
  - The Vision, Political Hydrophobia, showing the Comforts of Crowns and How to Obtain Them [Jackson], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-7)
    Drawn by Zek Downing. Published by E. Bisbee. Acquisition(?) date on back: Aug. 15, 1939.
  - Set to Between Old Hickory and Bully Nick [Jackson], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-8)
    Lithograph: Entered ... 1834 by A. Imbert ... Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - Riding on the Wrong Horse! [Jackson], circa 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-9)
    Woodcut. Several lines of dialogue below.
  - Jactson und Wolf (Jackson and Wolf) [Jackson and the Debt], circa 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-10)
    German. Woodcut. Anonymous. Shows Josef Ritner, Penn. Farmer, along side Jackson.
  - Banks & Bribery, vs. Balls & Bumbs, Scene 1st. [Jackson and U.S. Bank], 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-11)
    Drawn by Zek Downing. Published by E. Bisbee. Weitenkampf dates this. Color
  - Old Nick's New Patent Plan to Make Nova Scotia Tories, Federls Coodies, Hartford Conventioners, Nullifiers, National Republican Bankites, etc., circa 1834 (Folder FF-32, Item 1834-12)
    Published by A. Imbert. Weitenkampf dates this. Acquisition(?) date on back: Nov. 16, 1942.
  - Every Body's Album & Caricature Magazine (14 sheets), 1834-1835 (Folder FF-33, Item 1-14)
    British. The collection holds 14 of the 39 total sheets published under this title from 1834-35. Sheets in the collection are numbered 24, 25, 26, 27, 28, 30, 31, 32, 33, 34, 36, 37, 38, and 39. Caricaturist C.J. Grant. #24 was published by John Kendrick and printed by Dean & Munday. #25 and subsequent were printed and published by T. Dawson.
  - An Album, 1834-1835? (Folder FF-33, Item 15)
    One sheet of social caricatures, in color. No attributions. British(?) ("price 4d colourd, 2d plain")
  - The Abolition Garrison in Danger, & The Narrow Escape of the Scotch Ambassador [W.L. Garrison], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-1)
    Lithograph: Boston Oct. 21st, 1835. Noted as copy 1, and the card catalog indicates there are two copies, but there is no second copy in the file.
  - Funeral Obsequies of a Late Defunct Politician of the 4th Ward [Jackson], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-2)
  - Great LocoFoco Juggernaut, A New Console-a-tory Sub-Treasury Rag-Monster (above); To the Father of Shinplasters and Better Currency Chieftain. GOOD for a SHAVE (below) [Jackson], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-3)
    16 lines of verse below.
  - Chatham Theater. Orthodoxy in Sock and Buskin!! The New Means...Or, Raising the Wind. A Religious Farce in 4 Acts. [James Gordon Bennett], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-4)
    Signed H. in center. Below caricature is the text of the four acts.
  - A Democratic Voter [Abuses of Suffrage], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-5)
    Published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Signed N. Sarony. Acquisition(?) date on front June 3, 1908.
  - Democratic Simplicity. or The Arrival of Our Favourite Son. [Tammany Candidate], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-6)
    Published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front May 29/04(?).
  - The Experiment in Full Operation [Jackson], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-7)
    Published by A. Imbert, New York. Acquisition date on back Nov. 16, 1942
  - Dr. William Valentine In Some of his Eccentric Characters. Sketched by Dr. Northall of Brooklyn during an Entertainment [Social], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-8)
    N. Currier, Lith. New York. According to George Odell's "Annals of the New York Stage" Dr. Valentine made appearances in Brooklyn during the seasons 1835-6 and 1837-8.
  - Much Ado about Nothing or a Militia Court-Martial!!, 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-9)
    Published by Kimball, Boston. Note: This caricature is described as a skit on the militia. Col. [John] Pluck was an ignorant hustler who in 1824 was elected Colonel of the 84th Regiment of Pennsylvania Militia as a joke to ridicule the militia system. Acquisition(?)date on back: Dec. 6, 1950.
  - Pour un Pauvre Americain, S'il Vous Plait. [Spoliation Claim], 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-10)
    La Caricature, (Journal) No. 222 Pl. 463. Lithograph: Delaunois. Au bureau chez Aubert galerie Vero Dodat. Formerly in collection of James Hazen Hyde (stamp on back).
  - Southern Ideas of Liberty, 1835 (Folder FF-34, Item 1835-11)
    Below: Sentence passed upon one for supporting that clause of our Declaration viz. All men are born free & equal. "Strip him to the skin! give him a coat of Tar and Feathers!! Hang him by the neck, between the Heavens and the Earth!!! as a beacon to warn the Northern Fanatics of their danger!!!!" Acquisition(?) date on back: Dec 6, 1950
  - Houston, Santa Anna & Cos., 1836 (Folder FF-35, Item 1836-1)
    Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition(?) date on front July 12, 1904.
  - The Memorable Fire of April 4th 1836. Second and Third Street, Avenue D, Union Market [James Gulick?] (Folder FF-35, Item 1836-2)
    Signed H.R.
  - Cash Payment. Arrival of the French Cavalry. [French debt for damage to American ship], 1836 (Folder FF-35, Item 1836-3)
    Signed H. Published by H.R. Robinson, New York. Acquisition date on back Aug. 15, 1939. There is a second black & white copy (1836-3 Copy 2). Stamped on back "Gift of Henry O. Havemeyer, Yale 1900. Collection of United States Naval Prints and Paintings" and stamped on front "From Judge Mitchells Collection."
  - The Voice of the People [James Gulick], 1836 (Folder FF-35, Item 1836-4)
    Signed C. (E.W. Clay). Printed and published by H.R. Robinson, New York.
  - A Case of Cholera Morbus ...Drawing Out Deposites! [Federal Finance], 1836 (Folder FF-35, Item 1836-5)